William L. Daley Collection Relating to Billy Sunday
Manuscript Division, Library of Congress
William L. Daley Collection Relating to Billy Sunday 1914-1925
MSS01851
Sunday, Billy, 1862-1935
Daley, William L.
300 items
1 microfilm reel
Manuscript Division, Library of Congress Washington, D.C.
Evangelist, born William Ashley Sunday. Chiefly newspaper clippings compiled by Sunday's press agent concerning revivals held by Sunday. Also includes miscellaneous correspondence, sermon notes, brochures, and other printed matter.
Selected Search Terms
The following terms have been used to index the description of this collection in the LC Catalog. They are grouped by name of person or organization, by subject or location, and by occupation and listed alphabetically.
People
Daley, William L. William L. Daley collection relating to Billy Sunday. 1914-1925.; Sunday, Billy, 1862-1935.
Subjects
Evangelists--United States.; Revivals--Maryland--Baltimore.; Revivals--New Jersey--Trenton.; Revivals--New York (State)--Buffalo.; Revivals--New York (State)--Syracuse.; Sermons, American.
Titles
Billy Sunday papers
Occupations
Clergy.; Evangelists.
Provenance
The William L. Daley Collection Relating to Billy Sunday, compiled by his press agent, William L. Daley, was given to the Library of Congress by Dorothy H. Daley in 1967.
Transfers
Items have been transferred from the Manuscript Division to other custodial divisions of the Library. Photographs have been transferred to the Prints and Photographs Division. A book has been transferred to the Rare Book and Special Collections Division. All transfers are identified in these divisions as part of the William L. Daley Collection Relating to Billy Sunday.
Access and Restrictions
The Daley Collection is open to research. Researchers are advised to contact the Manuscript Reading Room prior to visiting. Many collections are stored off-site and advance notice is needed to retrieve these items for research use.
Microfilm
A microfilm edition of these papers is available on one reel. Consult reference staff in the Manuscript Division concerning availability for purchase or interlibrary loan. To promote preservation of the originals, researchers are required to consult the microfilm edition.
Biographical Note
Sunday, Billy
Date Event
1862, Nov. 19 Born near Ames, Iowa
1872 Sent by impoverished mother to orphanage in Glenwood, Iowa
1880 Moved to Marshalltown, Iowa
1883 Signed to play baseball by the Chicago White Stockings baseball club
1886 1887 Converted to Christianity and began attending the Presbyterian Church
1888 Sold to the Pittsburgh Alleghenys baseball club Married Helen Amelia Thompson
1890 1891 Played for the Philadelphia Phillies before retiring from baseball
1891 Became assistant secretary of the Chicago, Ill., YMCA
1896 1935 Conducted Christian evangelistic meetings throughout the country; credited with giving more than twenty thousand sermons to audiences totaling more than one hundred million people
1903 Ordained by the Presbyterian Church
1935, Nov. 6 Died, Chicago, Ill.
Scope and Content Note
The William L. Daley Collection Relating to Billy Sunday spans the years 1914-1925 and consists chiefly of newspaper clippings compiled by Sunday's press agent, William L. Daley, relating to revivals held by the evangelist in Syracuse, New York, 1915; Trenton, New Jersey, and Baltimore, Maryland, 1916; and Buffalo, New York, 1917. Also included is miscellaneous correspondence, sermon notes, brochures, and other printed matter.
Newspapers and newspaper clippings, which make up the bulk of the collection, were discarded after filming and are available only on microfilm.
Arrangement of the Papers
The newspapers, newspaper clippings, and correspondence are arranged chronologically.
Container List
Available on microfilm. Shelf no. 19,360
- Scrapbook of clippings, 1915-1917 (Box 1, Reel 1)
  Available only on microfilm
- Newspaper clippings (Box 1, Reel 1)
  - 1915 (Box 1, Reel 1)
  - 1916 (Box 1, Reel 1)
  - 1917 (Box 1, Reel 1)
  - 1918-1923 (Box 1, Reel 1)
  - Undated (Box 1, Reel 1)
  - Fragments (Box 1, Reel 1)
- Newspapers, 1923-1924 (Box 1, Reel 1)
- Correspondence, sermon notes, and various printed matter, 1916-1925 (Box 1, Reel 1)
- Photographs, undated (Box 1, Reel 1)
  Transferred to Prints and Photographs Division
- The Real Billy Sunday, by Elijah P. Brown (New York: Revell Co., 1914) (Box 1, Reel 1)
  Transferred to Rare Book and Special Collections Division [microfilm version is limited to cover, inscription, and title page]